So I am on the AWS console and let me just search for recognition.
So here we have Amazon recognition.
And now I'm on the homepage of Amazon recognition.
You can see on the left there are all the demos that provided
which given inside on the capabilities of Amazon recognition.
So we have the label detection here.
If you just click on this and then you can just select an image
either you can upload your own image or you can choose a sample image.
So if I just click on this and you can see it will detect all the
labels from the predefined labels that that they have.
So it's showing us architecture with 100% confidence,
building, city, cityscape, urban and so on.
And you can see some of the predefined list of labels that they have.
And you can just download the full list if you're interested.
Or you can also create some custom labels.
So that's on the label detection.
Next, it can also help to define the image properties.
So if you select an image here or you upload your own image,
then it can show you some of the image properties related to dominant colors,
bright and sharpness and so on.
Then third one we have is image moderation.
And we already discussed about it.
So if I just select an image here and then based on certain predefined labels,
it can determine whether the content is inappropriate or not.
Then it can do facial analysis and determine whether the person is smiling or
not, what is the age and and so on.
And you can upload your image as well.
And the next you have is face comparison and it can compare faces to see how
closely they are mashed based on similarity percentage.
So you can see you have a indigenous here and there's a 99.9% match on the images.
Then it can also do other things like celebrity recognition.
So from the images it can recognize who is the celebrity.
So if I now look at from the perspective of videos.
So now if I just click on stored video analysis,
you can see it can create various labels that it finds.
So you can see the adults clothing and it can create these tags.
And then file you have the streaming video event.
And here in the streaming video event machine learning based,
real time analysis of live videos to detect labels such as people,
pets and packages.
And if it detects some undesired activity,
then it can also send a notification in real time.
Okay, now let's just take a look at one of the real world use cases from AWS
on how they're using Amazon recognition.
So this is intelligent search media assets with Amazon recognition and Amazon
elastic search.
So this is about tagging and searching of media assets in industries like
median entertainment, manufacturing, education, etc.
So what they are doing is in a store or a manufacturing unit,
they take pictures and videos of all the assets they can find
and they just upload it in this S3 bucket.
So once the image is uploaded, it generates an event notification,
which goes to this Amazon Q service.
So once this message is in the SQS service and this lambda function is in work,
it makes an API call to this Amazon recognition.
And Amazon recognition then tags that image with some predefined labels.
So let's say they uploaded this image.
What Amazon recognition will do is it will apply some labels
based on the predefined labels that it's been trained on.
So maybe it will say, okay, this is apparel with 98.7% confidence.
It's a t-shirt, there's a person, there are some pills, etc.
So then all these tags would be stored.
Now the end user can search all the images that have been uploaded
in this S3 bucket through the Amazon elastic search.
So if there was a tag t-shirt assigned by Amazon recognition to this image,
when the user puts a search query on t-shirt,
then it's going to be able to retrieve this image.
So attach the link to this use case in the property in case you want to read through.
So that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see in the next lecture, thank you.